

Aleksandar Bakraceski

Senior Frontend Developer

Veselin Maslesha br3/2-2, Skopje, 1000, North Macedonia +38972565426 · <u>bakraceskia@gmail.com</u>

⇔ linkedin

Date / Place of birth

31.10.1994, Skopje

Nationality

Macedonian

Driving license

B category

Skills

Ability to Work in a Team

Problem Solving

Teamwork

Front End (Software

Engineering)

Dependency Injection

Blockchain

Classification And Regression Tree (CART)

Next.js

HTML5

Microsoft Word

Leadership

Skype

Profile

With over 8 years of experience in Front-End development, I specialize in building high-performance web applications using VueJS, ReactJS, PolymerJS, NodeJS, CSS, HTML and other FE frameworks/libraries as well as my collaboration with Back-End developers to create finished products-

. My projects have consistently resulted in improved performance and user satisfaction. I bring a proactive approach to project leadership and technical innovation.

Employment History

Senior Frontend Engineer, Synami, Skopje

March 2023 - Present

- Working on a project for Project Management in a small team of 5-10 people
- Implementation of new features, following Figma design provided by UI/UX designer
- Bug fixing and providing the best solution, focused on clean and reusable
- Improvement in code base and using the latest technologies for better performance and scalability
- Code review
- Used technologies and skills: VueJS, Vuex, Vuetify, Git, Tabulator.js, Typescript, ReactJS, Redux, NodeJS, Composables

Senior Software Engineer, HTEC, Skopje

July 2022 - March 2023

- · Working on a few different projects in a small teams
- Implementation of new features, following Figma design provided by UI/UX designer
- Improvement in code base and using the latest technologies for better performance and scalability
- Code review
- Used technologies and skills: VueJS, Vuex, Vuetify, Git, Typescript, ReactJS, Redux, NodeJS,
- · Making decisions about new technologies to use

Code Review
Scalability
Timelines
JQuery
Elasticsearch
Data Binding
HyperText Markup Language (HTML)
Concurrent Versions System (Software)
TypeScript
User Experience
JavaScript (Programming Language)
Vue.js
System Requirements
Binding
React.js
Three.js
NHibernate
User Experience Design (UX)
GraphQL
Automapper
Unit Testing
Cascading Style Sheets (CSS)
Web Applications
NodeJS

Senior Software Engineer, Scalefocus, Skopje

July 2021 — July 2022

- Working on a project for HP, in a team of 15+ people, CRUD operations, sort/filter/search and all features needed for HP project
- Implementation of new features, following Figma design provided by UI/UX designer
- Bug fixing and providing the best solution, focused on clean and reusable code
- Improvement in code base and using the latest technologies for better performance and scalability
- Code review
- Used technologies and skills: Git, Typescript, ReactJS, Redux, NodeJS, MUI, Apollo client and GraphQL
- Direct communication with client
- · Team Lead few months

Frontend Developer, Heart for Health ICT, Skopje

July 2020 — June 2021

- Working on a Medical portal project, divided in small teams of 4 people,
 CRUD operations, sort/filter/search and all features needed for the project
- Implementation of new features, following Figma design provided by UI/UX designer
- Bug fixing and providing the best solution, focused on clean and reusable code
- Improvement in code base and using the latest technologies for better performance and scalability
- Used technologies and skills : Git, Typescript, Vuejs, Vuex, Vuetify, RESTapiS

Senior Frontend Developer, qBit Solutions, Skopje

September 2018 — June 2020

Developing web and mobile blockchain applications using Vue.js, React, Javascript, HTML, CSS. Working on a few blockchain projects for trading (buy/sell) cryptocurrencies,log in/ log out, handle your personal wallet, follow your transactions, make it responsive and so many other features.

- Working on a blockchain project for trading with Crypto, in a team of 15+ people
- Implementation of new features, Login/LogOut, Bye/Sell crypto, Web3.js, MetaMask, following Figma design provided by UI/UX designer
- Bug fixing and providing the best solution, focused on clean and reusable
 code.
- Improvement in code base and using the latest technologies for better performance and scalability
- Code review
- Used technologies and skills: Git, VueJS, Vuex, Typescript, ReactJS, Redux, NodeJS, MUI, RestAPIs, Web3.JS, Metamask
- · Direct communication with client
- Team Lead

English

Frontend Developer, CodeIT Solution, Skopje

January 2020 - May 2020

Used React.js, Elasticsearch and other FE things to develop web application as a main framework

Team Lead, qBit Solutions

January 2019 - January 2020

- Leading a team of 3 FE developers
- Organizing daily meetings with team where we discusses about the tasks, solutions and sharing knowledge
- · Code review

Frontend Developer, Blueshift

October 2016 - September 2018

Programming 3D video games and web APPs using Javascript, Jquery, HTML, CSS, Polymer.js, Three.js

- · Working on 3D Games project using Three.js,
- Developing platform for creating CVs (create CV, update, delete and features for exporting in choosen template in PDF/Word),
- Also project for transport company (creating caterogies of vehicles, add, edit
 and delete vehicles) to know and follow all infos about each vehicle Main
 task in role: Develop and redesign UIs Develop optimized web applications
 with maximum speed and scalability Bug fixing

Oracle PL-SQL Programming Spd computing Aug 2016 - Sep 2016 (2 months)

Angular.js developer, ATS Macedonia, Skopje

June 2016 — July 2016

• Internship program

Education

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science and Engineering, FACULTY OF COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING, Skopje

September 2013 - August 2017

SUGS "Georgi Dimitrov"

January 2013 — January 2018

high school

January 2009 - January 2013

Courses

ReactJS: The complete guide (Hooks, Context, Redux), Udemy

September 2021 — September 2021